hey everyone welcome to another lesson
in the stores called automation course
today we are going to talk about image
based test automation
now in the previous session I talked
about how you can identify controls by
using anchor control and in this session
we are going to talk how you can
identify controls using image based test
automation
so it's one of uh the identification
mechanisms provided by Tosca among many
others
and this is useful when you are not able
to identify controls using uh different
properties right so it's not unique and
you cannot identify it using different
properties so at that time you have to
fall back on other mechanisms like the
anchor control which we have already
seen and now we are going to see uh
another one which is called image based
automation right
so uh it's the same scenario where we
are trying to use the Google Search
application to search for some uh
text right so we want to enter some
texture and we want to click on this
Google search button but this Google
search button is not unique that's we
have already seen uh there are two
search buttons with similar properties
and it's difficult to identify it using
those properties
so now what we'll do is we'll try to
identify this Google search button using
this particular image right so Tosca is
going to identify this using this image
and going to perform the required
operation okay
so let's see how how this will work okay
so I am in my module section I'm using
the same folder which is the Google
folder and I'm going to scan the
application which is our Chrome
application
so let's select uh our Google Chrome and
click on scan to scan the application
um it will open the scan window if it is
in basic you can click on Advanced
because we need the advanced view in
order to select the different
identification mechanisms uh now here we
are looking for the Google search button
right and this is the control which we
want to select
uh among some other controls like the
text button or the text bar right which
is obviously a unique control the text
box is a unique control so we don't need
to do anything here but for the Google
search uh we need to think about some
other mechanisms because this item is
not unique right
so I'm going to go to identify by uh
menu right and here we have already seen
properties which is the default one and
then we have also seen the anchor now
the third option we are falling back
upon is the image right so let's select
this and now this will open up our
window on the right hand side which is
called the identifier image
and as you can see it is already showing
you a control image right but uh
uh what if I want to identify this
control by the image itself right in
that case I need to add a image for this
particular control okay so here there is
an option uh a picture with a plus
button so I can select that and that
will automatically change the window and
the mouse pointer will change to a plus
sign which will tell you that you can
now select a particular control area
which can be uh selected as an image for
that particular control right so on the
right side you will see there is
information dialog which says you can
drag the cursor around the area used
fire identification you can also press
return if you want to use image of the
Define control area which you have
selected for identification
if you want to cancel this operation you
can always press Escape
uh the other thing to note here is uh
the cross sign and the save button so
the cross sign is uh to cancel this
particular operation the save option is
to just save the image which you have
selected right so uh although it is
already showing me uh the control area I
can also select my own control area as
you can see here right and that will
prompt me that whether I want to
consider image based identification
right
and the reason for this prompt is it is
saying that this might result in a long
duration without a visible x-can window
okay now there are a lot of factors when
it comes to image based automation we'll
talk about it but for now you can either
click on remember my decision and it
will not ask you again this prompt or
you can just select yes
and that way uh now we have added a
image for this particular control right
now the important thing to note here is
the image properties okay so if you see
down there are image properties uh we
can give it this image a name so I I'll
give it search
uh the important thing is the screen
resolution now I talked about different
factors when it comes to image based
test automation
the reason it is not the best option
when you are trying to automate the
application is because of these factors
right so screen resolution is one as you
can see it is one particular screen
resolution when I have added this
particular control right or the image
but what if during execution the screen
resolution changes to something else
then my image based automation is going
to fail right because it is dependent on
the resolution and lot of other things
like the offset which is the position of
the image which identifies that
particular control on the screen
uh then there is method which is
currently it is full screen but if it is
not full screen then also there is a
chance of failure right uh then there is
the accuracy as you can see it's not
hundred percent it's 95 percent
so all of these factors needs to be in
place if the image based automation is
going to work and it's a lot of factors
right so there is no guarantee it will
work every time but it is still an
option uh if there are no other options
uh no other ways to identify a
particular control in a application you
can always fall back upon this option
but it should be the last resort not the
first option right so you should always
go through the properties first then try
to use an anchor and then not then um if
all of these options are still not
working you can still fall back upon
this option which is identify by image
okay
so uh now we have selected um our Google
search and you can see here uh along
with the properties there is also a
image option right which is telling that
uh this particular control is using both
properties and image uh as a mechanism
to identify this item uniquely within
that particular screen or application
okay
so once you do that you can click on
Save and then click on close
so that will build uh the module okay so
we have got our module now which is uh
we have got our uh the text box and the
button here right
so let's go ahead and try it out
um I will
I've already created a test case folder
which is Island fiber image I just need
to add that particular module in order
to get it working right so let's first
create a test case here
so I will say search
by image
and here I just need to add my Google
module so I will say Google here
and this is the text box so I want to
enter here something like Tosca
uh in Google search which is the button
and here I'm going to click on it right
so that's that's the similar test case
which we have created earlier as well no
changes here it's just the module which
is changing because we are changing the
control
identification mechanism right
so let's go ahead and execute this and
we'll see if it is working or not
so as you can see it was able to enter
Tosca and it was able to uh click on
that particular button
but the only difference this time was we
have uh identified that particular
button using our image instead of only
Properties or anchor control right
so that's what is all about image based
automation uh in Tosca uh that's how you
can identify controls using images
um
it's one of the options but as I said
it's not always the best option
there are lots of other things in image
based test automation which we'll talk
about in the later sessions but
hopefully this was helpful
um in identifying controls by another
mechanisms which you can use while
working in Tosca
so that's all for this particular
session uh keep watching uh will be
coming up with more uh interesting Tosca
lessons so subscribe to our Channel and
see you in the next session